

RUBEN DORADO

• DETAILS •

(512)708-0500 rjdorado96@outlook.com

LINKS

LinkedIn Profile

o SKILLS o

Employee Recruitment & Retention

Employment Law

Conflict Management

Compensation & Benefits

Microsoft Office

Quickbooks

LANGUAGES

Spanish

HOBBIES

Web Development, Camping, Hiking, Fishing, Mountain Biking

PROFILE

Motivated Human Resources Professional (6 years experienced) with a drive for serving as a dedicated support specialist and dedicated team member. Adept in assisting with the recruitment of employees, as well as the management of existing employees. Experienced in managing employee success programs, and dedicated to working towards the mission of a company.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

HR Coordinator at Mend Services, Austin, TX

January 2021 — Present

- Administer screening candidates by reviewing resumes, applications, and performing more in-depth reference checks as needed.
- Served as the first point of contact for virtual and onsite employee inquiries.
- Managed virtual and onsite on-boarding and off-boarding.
- Collaborated with the company owner to meet and exceed all company initiatives for both office and field employees.
- Maintained extremely well organized records and handled all HR matters with confidentiality and the application of company standards.
- Recorded and reported employee issues, and brought them to upper management when necessary.
- Tracked HR issues to resolution and escalated as needed.
- Coached managers and employees on performance matters.
- Identified company setbacks and developed and implemented solutions.
- Effectively utilized Human Resources Information Systems.
- Completed HRIS data entry, reporting, auditing, and processed payroll requests.

HR Coordinator at Precious Metals Direct, Austin, TX

August 2019 — December 2020

Sales Ops. Duties:

- Assisted in establishing sales goals by forecasting annual sales quotas and projecting expected sales volume for existing and new products.
- Assisted in identifying and maximizing sales opportunities, and increased customer retention rates
- Analyzed sales and financial performances to effectively plan for increased future opportunities, while identifying obvious weak trends.

HR Duties:

- Managed sourcing, screening, interviewing, and placing of candidates.
- Assisted with payroll and distributed paychecks to employees.
- · Created and implemented a Conflict resolution program
- Administered benefit and compensation packages.

Operations Coordinator at U.S. Gold Bureau, Austin, TX

October 2018 — July 2019

 Generated weekly metric reports (Sales Forecasts, Lead conversion rates, monthly GP Breakdowns, etc..)

- Administered ADP time card adjustments/PTO approvals
- Coordinated sales floor audits
- Administrated bi-weekly incentive cash distribution to the sales floor
- Worked with Sales Operation Manager to generate leads, prospects, and customer lists for Sales Account Managers
- Assisted in coordinating company cultural/team-building activities and events

EDUCATION

Economics, Texas State University, San Marcos, TX
January 2016 — December 2018

1 REFERENCES

• References available upon request

COURSES

Front End + Mobile Development, Nucamp February 2022 — June 2022